ALETHIA O'HARA-STEPHENSON, CIP, BA, MBA

Shelburne, Ontario, L9V 2A5 **☎** (647) 210-1939 (647) 622-6958 ⊠ alethia.stephenson@gmail.com

8 February 2021

Attention: Jason Murray & Michael Williams

Re: Government of Canada BIPOC Executive Search

It is with keen interest that I present my resume to you for the for one of the BIPOC Executive Search opportunities with the Government of Canada. With several years of experience leading Diversity & Inclusion initiatives on both a corporate and community level working with senior leaders and all levels of local government, I am confident that my skillset will bring added value to your organization. I have over 20 years of progressive leadership experience within the Financial vertical of the Canadian banking industry working with executives, external and strategic partners along with several years project management, change management and supervisory experience leading cross-functional teams.

As a corporate and community leader I have a strong track record working with stakeholders to effect change on Diversity & Inclusion initiatives. Some of my relevant accomplishments include:

- Provided recommendations to RBC to provide mandatory Anti-Black Racism training for all leaders
- Provided recommendation to RBC to create Safe Space for all employees
- Establish a mentorship pipeline for BIPOC employees
- Unanimous approval by Council to formally recognize Black History Month in Dufferin County
- Unanimous approval by Council to raise the Emancipation/Pan African Flag at various municipal offices in Dufferin county for the first time
- Unanimous approval by Council to establish a Diversity, Equity & Inclusion committee in Dufferin County and embed as part of the County's strategic priorities going forward.
- Organized Diversity & Inclusion Townhall sessions and panel discussions with various community leaders including our Mayor, Deputy Mayor, Police Chief & Warden of Dufferin County
- Organized and Hosted Black History Month Panel Discussion and Celebrations
- Consulted by Dufferin County Offices, the Black, Sikh & Muslim Community on Diversity Initiatives

As a result of my leadership in the community, I was and honored when the Town of Shelburne Council unanimously appointed me as Chair of the Anti-Black Racism, Racism & Discrimination Task Force where our responsibility is to report back to council with final recommendations based on community feedback.

In 2020 I was awarded the Town of Shelburne's highest honor, the Community Excellence Award for my leadership and advocacy and bringing the community together. I was also recognized as one of this years Women of Influence, as a result of both my educational accomplishments and transformational initiatives in the community. Based on my education and experience, I am confident that I will bring value to the Government of Canada Team.

I look forward to discussing my qualifications with you in more detail. Thank you for your consideration.

Sincerely,

ALETHIA O'HARA-STEPHENSON, CIP, MBA

Shelburne, Ontario • L9V 2A5 • ☎ • (647) 210-1939 • (647) 622-6958 ⊠ <u>alethia.stephenson@gmail.com</u>

Executive Profile

A strong leader with about 20 years in the financial vertical of the Canadian banking industry offering outstanding presentation, communication, and cross-cultural team management skills. Experienced, result-oriented leader with an advanced knowledge and experience in diversity and inclusion strategic planning, training, and program implementation.

Skill Highlights

- Diversity & Inclusion Speaker
- Curriculum development and design experience
- Experienced facilitator, presenter and trainer
- Research Skills

- Demonstrated project management skills.
- Leadership cross-cultural communication skills
- Public and community relations skills
- Experienced manager and administrator

Professional Experience

JUNE 2020 – PRESENT: CHAIR, ANTI-BLACK RACISM, RACISM & DISCRIMINATION TASK FORCE, TOWN OF SHELBURNE

- Facilitated the development and approval of the Task Force mandate and Terms of Reference with support from Council and Staff.
- Facilitated the development of Task Force deliverables, including survey content, design, and marketing material.
- Chaired weekly Task Force meetings for decisions on \$12,000 budget expenditures, strategic planning, and timelines.
- Provided Task Force leadership to 13 individuals including the Chief of Police, Mayor & Deputy Mayor of Shelburne.
- Executed on-time, under-budget Task Force deliverables to adhere to project road map.
- Built consensus between Task Force members and devised innovative strategies to fulfill our mandate and gather critical input from key stakeholders and community members.
- Built relationships with strategic partners leading to presentations to the Task Force and recommendations on how we can make the community more equitable and inclusive for all.
- Prepared and delivered delegations before council to update on progress of the Task Force.

FEBRUARY 2019 - PRESENT: ADVISOR, BUSINESS CONTINUITY MANAGEMENT - ROYAL BANK OF CANADA (TORONTO)

- Consult and manage with tactical Business Continuity Management activities including business impact analysis, Business Continuity Plan Development, identify areas of emerging risk, test, verify and perform GAP closure on all assigned business functions/units, incident management procedures, support the local business units with specialized software.
- Review and challenge any instances of undue risk-taking by business and functional executives in the identification of risks, the definition of risk tolerances, the selection of continuity tasks and strategies or the testing of continuity plan resulting 98% compliance with Risk standards.
- Ensure all 125 business continuity plans comply with RBC Standards and Policy, coordinate reporting of compliance within the areas of responsibility.
- Partner with 12 regional / business line executive to create, coordinate and maintain a multi-discipline
 Incident management team to provide a resilient response for regional / business emergencies.

NOVEMBER 2016 - FEB. 2019: MANAGER, SUPPLIER MANAGEMENT, COORDINATION & SUPPORT - RBC INSURANCE, (MISSISSAUGA)

- Accountable for the end-to-end contractual relationship between RBC Insurance and strategic Business Process & IT Outsourcing with 8 suppliers.
- Accountable for the annual contractual spend of \$17 million plus additional ongoing development spend for each supplier both onshore and offshore.
- Facilitate ongoing BAU activities for 8 suppliers and develop BAU governance for new engagements.
- Lead Supplier Risk Review of 8 strategic suppliers with Information Security, Privacy and Third-Party Risk to mitigate and close 100% of findings within timelines.
- Lead the successful review and approval of PCI AOC and SOC 1 report with functional partners.
- Facilitate contract review and signoff with Procurement, Suppliers and RBC Senior Leaders
- Managed workload across a team of 4 Supplier Coordination & Support (SCS) personnel and over 500 indirect employees, ensuring good practices are established, documented, and executed. Key areas of focus include access management, invoice reconciliation/payment, and SLA tracking/reporting.

MAY 2014 - OCTOBER 2016: MANAGER, CONTRACTING & SUPPORT, LICENSING, CONTRACTING & COMPENSATION SERVICES - RBC INSURANCE, (MISSISSAUGA)

- Lead a cross functional team of 30 Contracting and Maintenance Administrators while managing team performance, SLA's, day to day operations and ongoing development and coaching.
- Build key relationships with business partners and over 100 Third-Party Agencies to support our business and streamline processes.
- Communicate change to all stakeholders including teams on various initiatives.
- Single point of contact for escalations and Third-party advisor complaints and follow ups.
- Successfully lead the Contracting and Support team through major transformational project resulting in operational efficiencies and cost savings through outsourcing
- Successfully transitioned 70 key processes to third party supplier while maintaining team morale and performance during and after transition

MARCH 2012 - MAY 2014: SUPPLIER RELATIONSHIP MANAGER - RBC INSURANCE, (MISSISSAUGA)

- Manage the end-to-end relationship of third-party suppliers including, contract management, financial and spend management, governance, due diligence, regulatory, security oversight and management, performance adherence to SLA and operational targets and accountable for the annual contractual spend of \$4 million plus additional ongoing development spend for each supplier.
- Perform regular vendor risk, financial and security assessments to determine risk with regards to financial solvency, business dependency, replacement time and cost, employee/client exposure, dollar spend reputation and ownership considerations and industry trends.
- Manage the ongoing relationship with functional partners supporting H&A, Life and Creditor products as it relates to third party vendors and represented the Vendor Management Team for all initiatives.

Education

Master of Business Administration (MBA)	Edinburgh Napier	2019		
Bachelor of Arts, Political Science (BA)	York University	2013		
Technical Writing Certificate	Humber College	2004		
Professional Development				
AODA Customer Service Standards		2014, 2012	_	
Managerial Excellence (MEx 100 Series)		2012		
Chartered Insurance Professional Designation (CIP) IIOC		2006		
Project Management course with RANA Development Inc,		2004		

Core Accomplishments and Community Highlights

-	Recipient of Community Excellence Award	2020
•	Recipient of Women of Influence Recognition	2020
•	Founder & President - Dufferin County Canadian Black Association	2020
•	Council Director - Shelburne Youth Advisory	2018 - Present
•	Facilitator & Speaker - Diversity & Inclusion Dufferin County	June 2018
•	Keynote Speaker - Black History Month	February 2020
•	Organizer - Dufferin County Black History Month	February 2020
•	Facilitator - Leadership, Ethics & People Management, Cleveland, Ohio	June 2019
•	Speaker & Presenter - Annual MGEF Conference- Edinburgh, Scotland	April 2019
•	Council Member - United Way Women's Leadership	2016 - 2018
•	RBC Caucus Member - Employee Giving & Diversity Expo	2014 – 2019
•	Ambassador - Charity Trust Junior Achievement	2010
•	Exam Invigilator - Insurance Institute	2006 - 2017
	Keynote Speaker - Education & Leadership, Montreal	2014